

website: neerajdesai.com

neerajdesai@outlook.com | 240.566.2353

I currently work as a software engineer at Lockheed Martin. I studied Architecture for a year and have been graphic designing for 6 years. I'm a passionate User Experience Designer with knowledge in the user-centered design. I advocate for user needs through planning, design and implementation ensuring all output reflects a solid understanding of UX principles. I have a strong desire to inspire creativity, innovative thinking and offer compelling solutions that translate into building worldclass interactive experiences and products across all digital platforms. I like tinkering with art and technology.

# **EDUCATION**

# Bachelors of Science, Computer Engineering (*Aug 2015*)

University of Maryland, Baltimore County

# SKILLS

#### Research and Design

Affinity Diagramming
Data Analysis
Heuristic Evaluation
Typography
User Research
Visual Design
Wireframing

#### **Programming**

C

HTML

Python

#### **Design Tools**

Adobe After Effects
Adobe Illustrator
Adobe InDesign
Adove Photoshop
Adobe XD
Procreate
Sketch

#### Communication

Collaborative
Creativel
ntuitive
Passionate
Problem Solver
Visionary

## **EXPERIENCE**

Lockheed Martin: Software Engineer (Sept 2015-Present)

- Tested LTE boards by writing test drivers saving the company over \$100k.
- Streamlined software configuration from local environments to enterprise servers, which increased efficiency by 75%.
- Wrote the deployment guide as well as maintained software baseline, build, and release.
- Identified technical obstacles, designed solutions and developed proof of concept to increase business opportunities.
- Reviewed technical documents, requirements, and maintained our Linux servers.
- Partnered with mangers, engineers, and designers to increase productivity and improve the automation to help reach customer's expectations.

Verizon Corporate: Procurement (June 2013-Aug 2013)

- Developed a system to automate procurement documents to increase efficiency by 50%.
- Evaluated requirements and suggested products and custom solutions.

SYP Group: Network Technician (May 2011-Jan 2012)

- Diagnosed and resolved our client's servers, hardware, and network related issues.
- Redesigned data network infrastructure and configured related hardware (servers, routers, hubs, firewalls, CAT-5 wiring).

### PERSONAL PROJECTS

visit neerajdesai.com to view these projects

User Experience Design: Place faces with Names	(Oct 2017)
Interaction Design: Amazon Payment	(Oct 2017)
User Interface: Zara Website Redesign Concept	(Oct 2017)
Product Design: Baby App Concept	(Oct 2017)
User Experience Design: Calorie App Concept	(Oct 2017)
JD Accounting Services: Logo Rebranding	(Oct 2017)